Register to The Lowell Mason Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series II
  - Topics and General, II.D
    - Beck, Lydia A., 1909-1914; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      3 autograph letters signed to Henry Lowell Mason laid in.
    - Beck, [Mary E. and Lucy M.], 1843-1853; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 33)
      Lowell Mason with the Becks.
    - Benson, F.A.
    - Bissell, T., 1861 Oct 14; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 34)
      From Lowell Mason. Includes note re provenance by Henry Lowell Mason.
    - Bliss, Abby Maria Wood (Mrs. Daniel) (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - Lowell Mason to Bliss., 1864 Jan 7; 2 items.
      - Bliss to Henry Lowell Mason, 1909; 2 items.
      - Henry Lowell Mason to Bliss., 1909-1910; 2 items.
    - Boggs, J., 1844 Jan 8; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Boston. Central Congregational Society. Committee on singing, 1843 Dec; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Boston. Committee for the improvement of music in certain churches, 1825-1827; 14 items. (Box 4, Folder 38)
      Includes a report, minutes, and autograph letter signed to Lowell Mason from the Committee.
    - Bowdoin Street Church, 1831-1843; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 39)
      Includes 5 autograph letters signed to Lowell Mason, and autograph letter signed from Lowell Mason to Miss Almira M. White.
    - Brooks, Edward, 1868 Dec 21; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 40)
      From Lowell Mason
    - Collamore, Davis (Box 4, Folder 41)
      - 2 autograph letters signed from Lowell Mason to Collamore, 1869-1870; 5 items.
        Including notes by Henry Lowell Mason.
      - Between Henry Lowell Mason and Marion Davis Collamore, and Davis Collamore & Co., 13 items.
    - Curwen, Rev. John, 1859 Nov 4; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Davis, George and Mercy S., 1852-1859; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 43)
      With Lowell and Abigail Mason. Note by Henry Lowell Mason included.
    - Denny, George
      See: Boston. Committee for the improvement of music in certain churches
    - Dickinson, Mr. and Mrs. John W., 1865-1871; 13 items. (Box 4, Folder 44)
      From Lowell Mason Note by Henry Lowell Mason re provenance laid in.
    - Erk, Ludwig Christian, 1865 Sep 21; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Fletcher, Katy, no date; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Fosdick, D., Jr., 1849 Nov 27; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 47)
      From Lowell Mason.
    - Grant, [Zilpah P.], 1876 Jul 4; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 48)
      From Lowell Mason Note by Henry Lowell Mason laid in.
    - Green, Mr., 1874 Jan 16; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Handel and Haydn Society, 1821-1832; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Holbrook, F., 1845 Jun 14; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 51)
      To Lowell Mason. Includes music.
    - Hood, Rev. George, 1864 Sep 9; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 52)
      From Lowell Mason Includes copy of signed autograph letter in the Allen A. Brown Collection of the Boston Public Library.
    - Hope, M.B., 1843 Jan 10; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Horn, Dr. F., 1869 Mar 30; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Jenks and Palmer, 1845 Aug 12; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 55)
      Receipt-note re provenance by Henry Lowell Mason laid in.
    - Killip, W.W., 1858-1864; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Kirk, Rev. Edward N., 1859 Jan 27; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 57)
      Includes typed letter signed and note by Henry Lowell Mason re the provenance laid in.
    - Lasar, Sigismund (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - From Lowell Mason, 1869 Oct 28; 1 item.
      - Between Henry Lowell Mason and others, 1872-1910; 8 items.
        Copies of letters, and a clipping (copy) re Lasar.
    - Lawrence, Rev., 1854 Jul 11; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 59)
      From Lowell Mason. Includes note by Henry Lowell Mason and typed letter signed re provenance laid in.
    - Lord, Melvin (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - Between Lowell Mason and Lord, 1856-1872; 9 items.
        Includes receipts, correspondence, and notes by Henry Lowell Mason re provenance.
      - Lord to Rev. John? Anderson (Louisville), 1855 Feb 26; 1 item.
      - With the Mason Brothers, 1855-1856; 9 items.
        Includes typed letter signed re provenance.
    - Lucas, George W., 1838 Mar 19; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Lyon, Mary, 1832 Nov 20; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Mann, Horace, 1844-1855; 16 items. (Box 4, Folder 63)
      To Lowell Mason. Includes notes by Henry Lowell Mason and clipping re provenance.
    - Morgan, John P., 1870 Apr 20; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Nägeli, Hans Georg (Box 4, Folder 65)
      - To Lowell Mason, 1837-1859; 5 items.
      - To Müller, 1837 Aug 2; 1 item.
    - Nason, Rev.?, 1857 Jun; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Neukomm, Sigismund, Ritter von, 1835-1848; 16 items. (Box 4, Folder 67)
      To Lowell Mason. Includes notes by Henry Lowell Mason.
    - Noyes, Daniel
      See: Boston. Central Congregational Society; and Boston. Committee for the improvement of music in certain churches.
    - Palmer, Rev. Dr. [Ray], 1857-1860; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 68)
      From Lowell Mason. Includes notes by and autograph letter signed (from Charles Ray Palmer) to Henry Lowell Mason re provenance.
    - Park, Rev. Dr. [Edward Amasa], 1959-1960; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Park Street Church. Committee on singing (Boston), 1930 Sep 24; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Parker, John Rowe
      See: Handel and Haydn Society.
    - Seeley, Rev. Raymond Hoyt, 1851 Apr 21; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Snelling, George Henry, 1840 Jan 1; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Upham, J. Baxter, 1869 Apr 14; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 73)
      To Lowell Mason. Also includes clippings (copies) and notes re provenance by Henry Lowell Mason.
    - Webb, George James, 1859 Jan 28; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Wells, Mason, 1872; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Wheeler, William A., 1863-1864; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Whittemore, Rev. Thomas, 1836; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 77)
      Includes Henry Lowell Mason's notes re provenance.
    - Willey, Austin, 1838-1850; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 78)
      From Lowell Mason. Includes Henry Lowell Mason's notes re provenance.
    - Winkler, ?, 1837 Oct 9; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Woodbridge, William Channing, 1837-1843; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 80)
      To Lowell Mason. Includes Henry Lowell Mason's notes re provenance.
    - Unidentified person, 1833 Jul 6; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 81)
      Includes notes by Eva J. O'Meara.
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, II.E
    - Gardiner, William, 1835 Feb 26; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 82)
      To ?
    - Tourjée, Eben, 1870 Dec 15; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Victor Talking-Machine Company, 1911; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Correspondence Concerning Henry Lowell Mason's Biography, etc., II.F
    - Anderson, Neal L., 1926 May 7; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Bartlett, Truman H., 1907-1909; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Bliss, Rev. Daniel, 1940-1941; 18 items. (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Bradbury, William F., 1910 Jun 15; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Clough, Frank H., 1935 Sep 11; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Crane, Theodore T., 1909; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Cumming, Montgomery, 1909; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Damrosch, Frank, 1910 Jun 15; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Dickinson, Edward, 1918-1932; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Duren, Elnathan F. and Mary, 1913 May 22; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Earhart, Will, 1918-1944; 20 items. (Box 4, Folder 93)
      Between Henry Lowell Mason and U.S. Department of the Interior. Office of Education, and William C. Hamilton.
    - Eliot, Charles William, 1909-1924; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Foster, Rev. Frank Hugh, 1919 Aug; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Fowle, Harriet Adams, 1909-1921; 11 items. (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Hillyer, Hattie Woodruff, 1909-1910; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Hyde, Constance, 1909 Aug 15; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Killip, William W., 1909-1969; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Krohn, Ernst C., 1936-1937; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Milligan, [Harold Vincent], 1910 May 2; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Root, Frederic W., 1909 Jun 20; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Sonneck Memorial Fund, 1942 Aug 1; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Stratford Company, 1921 Mar 12; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder lo4)
    - Sweet, Forest H., 1936-197; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Vosseller, Elias, 1913 Apr 19; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Warrington, James, 1910 Mar 16; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Westborough Historical Society, 1942 Jun 9; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Library Correspondence, II.G
    All correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender or recipient. Some cross-references exist from individual members to corporate entries. Recent library correspondence is housed in the reference file in the office.
    - Appel, Richard G., 1960-1972; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Boston Public Library, 1970; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Burial place, 1969; 7 items. (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Burt, Allan, 1946 Dec 9; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Carder, Polly (Mrs. A.W.), 1970-1972; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - Dealers, 1938-1961; 13 items. (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Dearing, Carroll M., 1971 May 18; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Ellis, Howard E., 1951-1954; 9 items. (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Endicott, Helen (Mrs. William), 1952-1972; 50 items. (Box 4, Folder 117-118)
    - Ginnell, Elizabeth Mason, 1970 Aug 7; 10 items. (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - Henderson, Hubert, 1972; 6 items. (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Kraege, Elfrieda A, 1972; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 121)
    - Krummel, Donald W., 1965; 2 items. (Box 4, Folder 122)
    - Larremore, Thomas A., 1953; 5 items. (Box 4, Folder 123)
    - Lyman, Ethel Louise, 1940 Jan 3; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 124)
    - Macdougall, Hamilton H., 1929 Aug 2; 1 item. (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Mason, Henry, 1933-1952; 104 items. (Box 4, Folder 126-128)
    - O'Meara, Eva Judd, 1965-1971; 26 items. (Box 4, Folder 129-130)
      (articles)
    - Pemberton, Carol, 1970-1972; 47 items. (Box 4, Folder 131-132)
    - Rich, Arthur L., 1945 Oct; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Rinck's library, 1938-1968; 22 items. (Box 4, Folder 134)
    - Rockwell, William Walker, 1940 Jan; 3 items. (Box 4, Folder 135)
    - Smith, Carlton Sprague, 1937 Oct; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 136)
    - Suehs, H.C., 1969 Aug; 4 items. (Box 4, Folder 137)
    - Thayer, Alexander Wheelock, 1961-1970; 12 items. (Box 4, Folder 138)
      (concerning him)
- Programs, Series III
  Loose program are arranged chronologically. The disassembled scrapbook is also arranged chronologically.
  - Loose programs, 1829-1976; 67 items. (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
  - Scrapbooks, 1829-1870 (Box 6)
    Assembled by Joel Sumner Smith? Contains mostly programs, with a few clippings and broadsides. Arranged chronologically. Originally 297 p.; 41 cm.
    Disassembled for preservation purposes. Table of contents in Smith's hand preserved, entitled: "Programmes preserved by Dr. Mason."
- Clippings, Series IV
  - General, IV.A
    Scope and Contents
    Contains loose clippings arranged chronologically.
    - Loose clippings, 1829-1974; 84 items. (Box 7, Folder 1-15)
  - Scrapbooks, IV.B
    - Scrapbooks, no date; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
      Containing a series of 24 articles by Lowell Mason for the Musical Review entitled "Choirs." Articles 27-29 are sketches in Lowell Mason's hand. Includes original and copy.
    - Scrapbooks, 1872-1899; 2 items. (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
      Containing obituary notices and other articles re Lowell Mason. Includes original and copy.
  - Miscellaneous Journals, IV.C
    Miscellaneous Journals probably in Lowell Mason's possession at the time of his death. Arranged alphabetically by title.
    See also: III. PROGRAMS. Scrapbook.
    - American musical journal, 1834-1835; 10 items. (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
      Contains article by or about Lowell Mason.
    - Journal of the society of arts, 1859 May 13; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Leipziger Zeitung, 1837 Jul 12; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Loomis' musical and masonic journal, 1875 Jun; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Minnesaenger, 1835; 4 items. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Musical world, 1852 Apr 1; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Neue Berliner Musikzeitung, 1852 May 19; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - New York Musical Gazette, 1866-1868; 3 items. (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Song messenger, 1872 Apr; 1 item. (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Writings, Series V
  - Diaries, V.A
    Arranged chronologically.
    - First visit to Europe, 1837; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
      Nos. 1-3.
    - Second visit to Europe, 1852-1853; 3 items. (Box 9, Folder 4-6)
      Nos. 4-6.
    - Unnumbered diary, 1852; 1 item. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Unnumbered diary, 1861; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Mrs. Lowell Mason. Journal", 1852; 1 item. (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Includes typescript transcription of a portion ([3] sheets) by Eva J. O'Meara.
    - [New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Library, 1970], 1 reel; 35 mm. (Box 16)
      Microfilm (negative) of the above journal.
    - [New Haven, Conn.: Yale University Library, 1972], 1 reel; 35 mm. (Box 16)
      Microfilm (negative) of the above 6 numbered diaries and Mrs. Mason's journal.
  - Miscellaneous Writings by Lowell Mason, etc., V.B
    Arranged alphabetically by title, miscellaneous items at the end.
    - The art of teaching singing according to the principles of Pestalozzi, no date; 3 items; [22] p.; 21-25 cm. (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Holograph sketch, in ink.
    - Choir practice on the Sabbath, 1856; 2 items; [18] sheets; 31 cm. (Box 10, Folder 4)
      "A series of six communications to the Editor of the Evangelist, 1856" - Henry Lowell Mason.
      Clipping and 3 sheets of notes laid in.
      "Received... from Mrs. Theodore F. Seward, February, 1917" - Henry Lowell Mason.
    - A glance at Pestalozzianism, [1868]; 3 items; 23 p.; 24 cm. (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Exhibit card included.
    - How shall I teach?, no date; 2 items; 12 p.; 24 cm. (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Fragments of lecture notes, no date; 4 items; 4 sheets; 19-23 cm. (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Holographs in ink.
      Includes: "Sundry memorandums for Teaching Book"; and 3 unidentified fragments.
    - Miscellaneous announcements and advertisements for hymn books co-authored by Lowell Mason, ca. 1858 Jul; 6 items. (Box 10, Folder 8)
      The Sabbath hymn book
      The Sabbath tune book
      The Sabbath hymn and tune book
      The Sabbath school hymn and tune book
- Biographical Information, Series VI
  - Miscellaneous Biographical Material, VI.A
    Arranged alphabetically by author.
    - Sermon: commemorative of Dr. Lowell Mason. - S.l.: Cushing, Bardua & Co., 1872., Bacon, George B. (George Blagden), 1836-1876; 2 items; 22 p.; 20 cm. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Photocopy included.
    - Commemorative booklet: Westborough, Massachusetts. - North Conway, New Hampshire: Reporter Press, 1967., Dearing, Rachel R.; 1 item; 176 p.; 25 cm. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Lowell Mason's contribution to the early history of music education in the United States. - [Columbus]: Ohio State University Press, 1937., Flueckiger, Samuel Lehmann; 1 item; pp. 77-85; 23 cm. (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Abstract of doctoral dissertation.
      Inscription to Eva J. O'Meara by author on cover, and letter from author to O'Meara (1970) laid in.
    - A history of the Highland Avenue Congregational Church., Highland Avenue Congregational Church (Orange, N.J.); 1 item; [12] p.; 29 cm. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Dated: 1980.
    - Biographical notes., Howard, John Tasker; 1 item; [30] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 4)
      Manuscript (photocopy).
    - Hymn tunes of Lowell Mason., Larremore, Thomas A.; 1 item; 6, [2] sheets; 28 cm. (Box 11, Folder 5)
      Typescript (copy).
      Dated: "1953 Apr 8."
    - Hymn tunes of Lowell Mason: a bibliography... - Cambridge, Mass.: The University press, 1944., Mason, Henry Lowell, 1864-1957; 1 item; 118 p.: port.; 24 cm. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous Biographical Material, O'Meara, Eva Judd; See: II. F. CORRESPONDENCE. Library Correspondence.
    - Lowell Mason. - Chapel Hill: The University of North Carolina Press, 1946., Rich, Arthur Lowndes; 1 item; vii, 224 p.: port.; 23 cm. (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Educational work of Dr. Lowell Mason. - S.l.: s.n., [1885?]., Seward, Theodore R.; 1 item; 32 p.; 20 cm. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Published with A.W. Thayer's "Lowell Mason."
    - Lowell Mason. - S.l.: s.n., [1885?]., Thayer, Alexander Wheelock, 1817-1897; 1 item; 32 p.; 20 cm. (Box 11, Folder 8)
      Published with the above.
    - Divinity School. - Exercises at the opening of "The Lowell Mason Library of Music," in the Yale Divinity School...", S.l.: s.n., ca. 1875 May 11.; Yale University; 1 item. (Box 11, Folder 9)
      28 p.; 23 cm.
    - Miscellaneous jottings, pamphlets, correspondence, articles, etc., 33 items. (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
      Containing biographical and genealogical information. Includes 2 jottings in Lowell Mason's hand, as well as manuscripts, typescripts, and copies.
  - Henry Lowell Mason's Biography, VI.B
    - Lowell Mason: his life and work., Mason, Henry Lowell, 1864-1957; 3 v.; 29 cm. (Box 12)
      Typescript with markings.
      Photographs, etc. attached.
      "Incomplete, ends at August, 1852" - note on title page.
    - Cancelled pages, notes, and references for the biography., 61 items. (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
- Memorabilia, Series VII
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Documents, 1845-1891; 9 items. (Box 13, Folder 1-3)
    Contracts, will, and recommendation. Original, typescripts, and photocopies (in part, negative).
  - Pamphlets, broadsides, tickets, invitations, etc., 1832-1948; 16 items. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 30 items. (Box 13, Folder 5-7)
    Of Lowell Mason, family, friends, locations, etc.
    For an engraved portrait of Lowell Mason in the Music Library Collection see the Portrait File.
  - Realia
    - Portrait medallion, 1911; 1 item. (Box 13, Folder 8)
      See also: II. E. CORRESPONDENCE. Miscellaneous Correspondence. Victor Talking Machine Company, 1911 May 6.
    - Explanatory notes to a new system of teaching the science of music... - Columbus Scott & Douglass., 1839; Winicker, A.C.; 1 item; 16 p.; 23 cm. 1 revolving chart (3 wheels). (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Writings and jottings by others., 8 items. (Box 13, Folder 10)
- William Mason, Series VIII
  Contains the papers of William Mason.
  - Piano Music by or Arranged by William Mason, VIII.A
    - [Ah! Vous dirais-je maman] Ah! Vous dirais-je maman: caprice grotesque. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1864., 9 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 1)
      Contains markings.
    - [Berceuse] Berceuse: op. 34. New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1871., 11 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 2)
      (New and revised edition).
    - [Capriccio fantastico] Capriccio fantastico: op. 50. New York G. Schirmer, c1897., 11 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Caprice grotesque
      See: Ah! Vous dirais-je maman.
    - [Characteristic sketches] Three characteristic sketches: op. 35. - New York: Edw. Schuberth, c1876., 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - [Dance antique] Dance antique: op. 33. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - [Dance caprice] Dance caprice: op. 36. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - [Dance rustique] Dance rustique: op. 16. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1860., 10 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - [Dance rustique] Dance rustique: op. 16. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1888., 9 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - [Improvisation] Improvisation: op. 51. - New York: G. Schirmer, cl900., 9 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - [Lullaby] Lullaby: op. 10. - New York: Firth, Son, c1857., 6 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - [Melody] Melody: op. 40. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - [Minuet] Minuet: op. 43. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 6m. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - [Monody] Monody: op. 13. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1892., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - [Pell-mell] Pell-mell: Galop fantastique ... op. 29 - New York: Charles Bruce, c1870., 13 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - [Les perles de rosée] New York: Schuberth, c1849., 13 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - [Prelude] Prelude: op. 30. - Boston: Koppitz Prüfer, c1870., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - [Prelude in F] Philadelphia: Theodore Presser, c1895., [2] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - [Rêverie poétique] Rêverie poétique: op. 24. - New York: G. Schirmer, c1885., 9 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - [Rêveries. Au matin] Deux rêveries...: op. 19. - New York: Firth, Pond, c1860., 9 p. of music; 32 cm. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - [Romance - etude] Romance - etude: op. 32. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1899., 9 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - [Romance - idyl] Romance - idyl: op. 42. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - [Scherzo] Scherzo: op. 41. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 10 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - [Serenata] Serenata: op. 39. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - [Silver Spring] Silver Spring: op. 6. - New York: Firth, Pond, c1856., 15 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - [Silver Spring] Silver Spring: op. 6. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1885., 15 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - [Spring-dawn] Spring-dawn: op. 20. - New York: G. Schirmer, no date, 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - [Toccata] Toccata: op. 37. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1882., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Toujours (Box 14)
      See: Valses de salon. Toujours.
    - [Valse de bravoure] Valse de bravoure: op. 15 [ie., 55]. - Boston: Nathan Richardson, c1854., 17 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - [Valse - impromptu] Valse - impromptu: op. 28. - Boston: Koppitz Prüfer, c1869., 10 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - [Valses de salon. Toujours] Valses de salon. Toujours: op. 7. no. 2. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1856., 7 p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - [Bishop, Sir Henry Rowley] Home sweet home: a one-finger pedal study for the piano-forte. - Philadelphia: Theodore Presser, c1904., 3 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 29)
      Arranged by William Mason.
    - Air à la bourée / by William Mason. - New York: Wm. A. Pond, c1874., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; 6 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 30)
      Transcribed by William Mason.
    - Bourée by G.F. Händel: (free transcription for the pianoforte) / William Mason. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1888., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; 3 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - G.F. Handel's celebrated Largo / arranged by Wm. Mason. - New York: Edward Schuberth, c1877., Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759; 5 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, VIII.B
    From William Mason to others, arranged alphabetically by recipient unless otherwise stated.
    - Blodget, D.? B., 1900 Aug 7; 2 items. (Box 14, Folder 31)
      Includes 2 bars of music.
    - Dunn, Sara A., 1898 Aug 19; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Pray, Florence M., 1936 Jan 9; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Sternberg, Constantin von, 1908 Feb 26; 1 item. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Van Gerbig, ?, 1904-1905; 4 items. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Weyman, Wesley, 1898-1903; 24 items. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Clippings, VIII.C
    - Articles by and about William Mason, 1853-1933 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Items, VIII.D